DAVID ALAGOA **UI/UX & GRAPHIC DESIGNER** 

Email: davidalagoa@gmail.com

**PROFILE** 

I am a passionate graphic and UI/UX designer with a background in Electrical and

Electronics Engineering and significant experience in the field of design. A creative and

highly organized individual, I strive to portray imperfect perfections through my works,

from logos, posters, and branding, to websites and mobile apps, while developing

empathy for users and understanding their needs. My goal is to apply my skills in an

environment which encourages creativity, learning and growth in the Advertisement and

User Interface and Experience aspects of digital technology using the knowledge

received from my previous engineering background and present design skills.

**EXPERIENCE** 

**Chief Design Officer** 

SiriusLabs (February 2019 – Till Date)

Implementing design systems and principles in projects

Handling creative aspects of projects, aligned with illustration and graphic design

principles

Designing wireframes, high fidelity sketches, prototypes for development

Performing user experience research and analysis of products for clients

Contributing to front end development aspects of projects

Freelance UI/UX and Brand Designer

(September 2018 – Till Date)

Illustrations and UX research for start-up fashion brands.

Collaborating with teams remotely on design projects.

• Offering consultations on design strategies to start-up companies and incubation

hubs.

Designing logos and illustrations for clients in various industries

### **Product Designer (Hardware/Digital)**

**VNTS (July 2018 – January 2019)** 

- Designing product hardware and contributing to device construction.
- Conducting customer research on device usage and functionality.
- Assisting and designing email and social media templates for email push-outs.

### **Sortation Associate**

Amazon Logistics, Maidstone, United Kingdom (November 2017 – January 2018)

- Sorting and arranging incoming parcels for processing
- Working with teams to scan parcels and packages for outgoing delivery

#### Student Advisor

ONCampus Coventry, United Kingdom (July 2017 - November 2017)

- Offering assistance and guidance students in enrollment process
- Contacting and receiving feedback from prospective students in admission process
- Arranging data for Marketing Manager for analysis

### **Junior Writer and Content Contributor**

StyleMania Magazine, Lagos. (December 2013 – July 2014)

### **RF Engineering Intern**

InterWireless Consultancy, Lagos. (May 2012 –April 2013)

- Conducted benchmark and drive tests to measure quality of 2G/3G service against regulatory KPIs.
- Carried out network tuning of base transceiver station (BTS) to improve network coverage and reception.

Collected and collated data such as Receiving Levels (RxLev), Voice Quality (RxQual) etc to support senior management with strategy planning.

### **EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATION**

# Product Design (Digital User Interface and Experience) Univelcity, Lagos, Nigeria

- Web and mobile user interface design
- Web and mobile user experience design
- Wireframing and prototyping
- Customer Journey Mapping

### **Electrical-Electronics Engineering (M.Sc)**

# Coventry University, United Kingdom (2016 – 2017)

- Completed a project on Alternative Energy, specifically in photovoltaic module optimization using MATLAB.
- Contributed to research on different optimization algorithms for France RTC solar panels.
- Carried out tests on DC and Induction motors; also used MATLAB for simulation of H-bridge as a DC-DC converter for power electronics applications.
- Conducted research on the UK power grid; monitoring peak and off-peak load performance and analysis demand.
- Did courses and projects on LED Matrix displays and Audio Propagation using VHDL test bench
- Performed edge detection and further image processing techniques in MATLAB.
- Applied Embedded C in PIC18 Microprocessors using Proteus and MPLAB. Also designed and implemented different projects involving PCB layouts such as the design of a digital IC tester with an HC-06 Bluetooth communication link

# **Electrical-Electronics Engineering (B.Sc)**

**University of Lagos (2006 – 2014)** 

- Studied modules: Circuit Theory, Introduction to Power Systems, Computer Programming (C++ and MATLAB), and Control Systems.
- Final project on the design and implementation of a temperature-controlled fan using a thermistor as temperature sensor.

## **O-levels**

**King's College, Lagos (1999 - 2005)**